[
  {
    "topic": "C-Plus-Plus",
    "subtopic": "Class and Objects",
    "type": "MCQ",
    "question": "How do you call a function getRollNo from object S1 of class Student?",
    "options": [
      "S1.getRollNo()",
      "S1::getRollNo()",
      "getRollNo()",
      "S1.function(getRollNo())"
    ],
    "answer": 0,
    "difficulty": "Medium"
  },
  {
    "topic": "C-Plus-Plus",
    "subtopic": "Basics",
    "type": "MCQ",
    "question": "Which of the following is the scope resolution operator?",
    "options": ["::", "~", "*", "."],
    "answer": 0,
    "difficulty": "Easy"
  },
  {
    "topic": "C-Plus-Plus",
    "subtopic": "Pointers",
    "type": "MCQ",
    "question": " Which of the following is illegal?",
    "options": [
      "int *ip;",
      "string s, *sp = 0;",
      "int i; double* dp = &i;",
      "int *pi = 0;"
    ],
    "answer": 2,
    "difficulty": "Easy"
  },
  {
    "topic": "C-Plus-Plus",
    "subtopic": "Basics",
    "type": "MCQ",
    "question": "Output of following CPP Code:\n int i=5;\ni= i++ + ++i;\ncout<<i;",
    "options": ["12", "11", "13", "Error"],
    "answer": 0,
    "difficulty": "Easy"
  },
  {
    "topic": "C-Plus-Plus",
    "subtopic": "Recursion",
    "type": "MCQ",
    "question": "Value of func(8): \nint func(int n){\nif(x<=0)return 0;\nelse{return func(x-2)+x;}",
    "options": ["23", "20", "21", "18"],
    "answer": 1,
    "difficulty": "Easy"
  },
  {
    "topic": "C-Plus-Plus",
    "subtopic": "Object Oriented Programming",
    "type": "MCQ",
    "question": "When is a Copy Constructor Called?",
    "options": [
      "An object of the class is returned by value",
      "An object of the class is passed by value as an argument",
      "When an object is constructed based on another object of the same class",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": 3,
    "difficulty": "Medium"
  },
  {
    "topic": "C-Plus-Plus",
    "subtopic": "Pointer",
    "type": "MCQ",
    "question": "Which of the following declarations points to a constant integer",
    "options": ["int * const", "int const *", "int *", "None of the above"],
    "answer": 1,
    "difficulty": "Easy"
  },
  {
    "topic": "C-Plus-Plus",
    "subtopic": "Basics",
    "type": "MCQ",
    "question": "C++ is a _?",
    "options": ["object oriented programming language", "procedural programming language", "both procedural and object oriented programming language", "functional programming language"],
    "answer": 2,
    "difficulty": "Easy"
  },
  {
    "topic": "C-Plus-Plus",
    "subtopic": "Object Oriented Programming",
    "type": "MCQ",
    "question": "Virtual inheritance in C++ is used to ?",
    "options": ["enhance multiple inheritance", "ensure that a private member of the base class can be accessed", "avoid multiple inheritances of classes", "avoid multiple copies of the base class into children/derived class"],
    "answer": 3,
    "difficulty": "Medium"
  },
  {
    "topic": "C-Plus-Plus",
    "subtopic": "Basics",
    "type": "MCQ",
    "question": "Which keyword is used to define the macros in c++?",
    "options": ["#define", "#macro", "macro", "define"],
    "answer": 0,
    "difficulty": "Easy"
  },
  {
    "topic": "C-Plus-Plus",
    "subtopic": "Basics",
    "type": "MCQ",
    "question": "Which symbol is used to declare the preprocessor directives in C++?",
    "options": ["$", "^", "#", "*"],
    "answer": 2,
    "difficulty": "Easy"
  },
  {
    "topic": "C-Plus-Plus",
    "subtopic": "Basics",
    "type": "MCQ",
    "question": "Choose the operator which cannot be overloaded in C++",
    "options": ["/", "()", "::", "%"],
    "answer": 2,
    "difficulty": "Medium"
  },
  {
    "topic": "C-Plus-Plus",
    "subtopic": "Basics",
    "type": "MCQ",
    "question": "What is the full form of STL?",
    "options": ["Standard template library", "System template library", "Standard topics library", "None of the above"],
    "answer": 0,
    "difficulty": "Easy"
  },
  {
    "topic": "C-Plus-Plus",
    "subtopic": "Basics",
    "type": "MCQ",
    "question": "Which operator has highest precedence?",
    "options": ["=", "()", "*", "++"],
    "answer": 1,
    "difficulty": "Medium"
  },
  {
    "topic": "C-Plus-Plus",
    "subtopic": "Basics",
    "type": "MCQ",
    "question": "What following operator is called '?:' ",
    "options": ["Conditional Operator", "Scope Resolution Operator", "Ternary Operator", "if else o/p"],
    "answer": 2,
    "difficulty": "Easy"
  },
  {
    "topic": "C-Plus-Plus",
    "subtopic": "Basics",
    "type": "MCQ",
    "question": "In C++ Program, inline functions are expanded during",
    "options": ["Debug Time", "Compile Time", "Run Time", "Coding Time"],
    "answer": 2,
    "difficulty": "Easy"
  },
  {
    "topic": "C-Plus-Plus",
    "subtopic": "Object Oriented Programming",
    "type": "MCQ",
    "question": "Number of Arguments in a Default constructor is",
    "options": ["0", "1", "2", "None of these"],
    "answer": 0,
    "difficulty": "Easy"
  }
]
